# **Prateek Mehra**

UX DESIGNER

http://prateekmehra.com

pmehra@uw.edu 206.953.0401 Seattle, WA

#### **UX PROJECTS**

# Clothing the Recycling Gap / UX Research & Design

October 2018 - December 2018, UW HCDE Course Project

Prototyped a mobile app to help households in King County recycle their clothes. Shared findings with King County and City of Seattle.

# NavAR Glasses / UX Design & Video Prototyping

October 2018 - December 2018, UW HCDE Course Project

Conceptualized a navigation experience for glasses based on a competitive product survey and user interviews.

# Virtual Auto Expo / Data Visualization & UX Design

October 2018 - December 2018, UW HCDE Course Project

Designed and developed a dashboard to help automobile buyers and businesses compare vehicles on performance and industry standards using D3.js.

# Go! Classroom / UX Design & Development

April 2014 - May 2014, IIITD, HCI Course Project

Designed and developed an Android application for reservation of classrooms and sending reminders about lectures and venues to students.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Myntra / Product Design & Development

India's largest fashion e-commerce platform

#### **Software Engineer**

July 2015 - October 2016

- Prototyped a look generation Fashion bot
- Shipped a workflow management system; designed and developed the UI for seamless fabric acquisition
- Improved reliability for high throughput services (likes and user profile) in story distribution platform (scaled to 10x throughput)
- Re-engineered scheduling and expiration flows on in-house content moderation (frontend) and publishing (backend) services

#### **Software Engineer Intern**

December 2014 - April 2015

Prototyped a gesture-based AR application simulating a trial room experience with real-time cloth simulation.

#### **RECOGNITIONS**

Winner Boeing Innovation Challenge January 2019
Finalist Facebook's Design in the Wild contest January 2019

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Washington**

MS in Human Centered Design and Engineering

September 2018 - May 2020

GPA: 4.0

Electives: User-Centered Design, Information Visualization, Video Prototyping, Visual Communication

### IIIT-Delhi

BTech in Computer Science and Engineering

July 2011 - May 2015 GPA: 8.97/10

#### **SKILLS**

## **UX Methods**

Storyboarding
Interaction Design
Wireframing
Video Prototyping
Rapid Prototyping
Visual Communication
Survey
Contextual Inquiry
Interview
Affinity Diagrams
Usability Testing

## **Tools**

Sketch
Adobe Creative Suite
InVision
Unity
FCPX/Motion

# **Development**

HTML/CSS JavaScript Python Java